Guide to the Yale Divinity School Faculty Writings and Publications
Yale University Divinity School Library
Yale Divinity School Faculty Writings and Publications
1843-2011
RG 27
Yale University Divinity School Library
16
(38 boxes)
This collection contains article-length publications and unpublished papers by Yale faculty, primarily from the Divinity School. These writings have been gathered into the collection in order to provide a consolidated repository for the works of Yale Divinity School faculty, past and present. This is not a comprehensive collection but rather consists of writings that have been given to the library by current or past Yale faculty members.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1701, Yale College was a place "wherein Youth through the blessing of Almighty God may be fitted for Publick employment both in Church and Civil State." In 1822 the Divinity School became a separate school within the University and now is one of eleven graduate and professional schools, which, with the College, comprise Yale University. Yale University Divinity School provides three degree programs: the Master of Divinity, the Master of Arts in Religion, and the Master of Sacred Theology.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains article-length publications and unpublished papers by Yale faculty, primarily from the Divinity School. These writings have been gathered into the collection in order to provide a consolidated repository for the works of Yale Divinity School faculty, past and present. This is not a comprehensive collection but rather consists of writings that have been given to the library by current or past Yale faculty members. Booklength writings by faculty members are included in the Library's regular cataloged collection.
The collection does not contain writings of individuals for whom we have separate personal papers collections. These include: Ahlstrom (Sydney) Papers:(RG 83) Bainton (Roland) Papers: (RG 75) Brown (Charles Reynolds) Papers: (RG 37) Burrows (Millar) Papers: (RG 71) Daggett (Oliver Ellsworth) Papers: (RG114) Davies (Henry) Papers: (RG85) Dittes (James E.) Papers: (RG 174) Fitch (Eleazar) Papers: (RG 93) Forman (Charles) Papers: (RG110) Frei (Hans) Papers: (RG 76) Holmer (Paul) Papers: (RG 195) Keck (Leander E.) Papers: (RG 256) Latourette (Kenneth Scott) Papers: (RG 3) Lindbeck (George) Papers: (RG 172) Macintosh (Douglas Clyde) Papers:(RG 50) McGee Street (Lee) Papers: (RG 229) Miller (Randolph Crump) Papers: (RG 173) Morris (Raymond) Papers: (RG 80) Pope (Liston) Papers: (RG 49) Pope (Marvin) Papers: (RG 135) Porter (Frank Chamberlin) Papers: (RG 119) Sanders (Frank Knight) Papers: (RG 122) Shedd (Clarence Prouty) Papers: (RG 35) Slie (Samuel) Papers: (RG 111) Tweedy (Henry Hallam) Papers: (RG 131) Veith (Paul H. ) Papers: (RG 59) Walker (Williston) Papers: (RG 51) Wright (Henry Burt) Papers: (RG 40)
In addition, the following faculty members have more substantial collections in Record Group No. 30, Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection: John Clark Archer Benjamin W. Bacon John A. Bollier Nils A. Dahl George Park Fisher Samuel Harris Hugh Hartshorne Paul Schubert George Barker Stevens Charles Cutler Torrey
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by faculty name.
Educators
- Faculty A-L
  - Adams, Harry Baker
    - Behold! God...Curriculum Area Guide, with Manette Adams. Christian Board of Publication, 1963. (Box 1)
    - Behold! God...Camper's Source Book, with Manette Adams. Christian Board of Publication, 1963. (Box 1)
    - Creative Tensions in Preaching: The Leslie R. Smith Lectures in Preaching and Worship (1988). Lexington Theological Quarterly Vol. 24, Numbers 1,2., 1989 (Box 1)
    - Seeking the Christian Way. Christian Board of Publication, 1965. (Box 1)
    - The Life of Faith in God. (Christian Discipleship Studies). Christian Board of Publication, 1965. (Box 1)
    - God Confronts Man. (Christian Life Curriculum). Christian Board of Publication, 1969. (Box 1)
    - Priorities and People. Bethany Press, 1975. (Box 1)
    - Growing Together. ("Living the Word" Leader's Guide, Level 9, Adult, Fall 1978). Christian Board of Publication. (Box 1)
    - Today's Word for Adults. (Vol. 1, Course 1, Fall 1978). Christian Board of Publication. (Box 1)
    - Pentecost 2, with Paul S. Minear. (Proclamation 2). Fortress Press, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Ahlstrom, Sydney E.
    Scope and Contents
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 83.
  - Allen, Michael
    - Teaching Students to See the Patterns of Eternity and Hope. Yale Alumni Magazine: April, 1971. (Box 1)
  - Archer, John Clark
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 30, Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection.
  - Attridge, Harold W. L.
    - CV and bibliography of writings, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Beyond Judaism and Hellenism, International Journal of the Classical Tradition v.6.1, 1999 (Box 2)
    - The Gospel of Truth as an Esoteric Text, in Nag Hammadi, Gnosticism, and Early Christianity., 1986 (Box 2)
    - Intertexuality in the Acts of Thomas, Semeia 80., 1997 (Box 2)
    - Johannesevangelium," in Hans Dieter Betz, et al., eds., Religion in Geschichte und Gegenwart, 2001 (Box 2)
    - "Seeking" and "Asking" in Q, Thomas, and John, in From Quest to Q., 2000 (Box 2)
    - VHS tape "Yale Professor Harold Attridge Speaks About DaVinci Code" - from KNTV, San Francisco program, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Bacon, Benjamin Wisner
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 30, Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
  - Bainton, Roland H.
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Groups No. 75 and 43.
  - Bartlett, David L.
    - The Gospel is Still News: Address before Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board of American Baptist churches, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Berger, Teresa
    - Articles and essays
      - CV and bibliography of writings, 2014 (Box 33)
      - Auf dem Weg zu einer "frauen-gerechten" Liturgie. 17 Gottesdienst, 22.Jahr, 20.September 1988, pp. 129-131. (Box 33)
      - Auf der Suche Nach Einer – Integrativen Liturgie. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 37.Jahr, Heft 1, 1987, pp. 42–58. (Box 33)
      - Benedictio nuptiarum. Eheschliessung – mehr als ein rechtlich Ding., 1989, pp. 164-180. (Box 33)
      - Bewegter und bewegender Glaube: tanzend zwischen Gott und Welt. Lebendige Katechese, v. 10, (1988), pp. 125-127. (Box 33)
      - Bibel und Liturgie. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 42.Jahr, Heft 1, 1992, pp. 70-78. (Box 33)
      - Das brot des lebens im land des fast food. Bible und Kirche, 57.Jahrgang, 1.Quartal 1/2002, pp. 36-37. (Box 33)
      - Brot und Stein. ZG&P, 18.Jahrgang, Heft 2/2000, pp. 10-12. (Box 33)
      - Busse und Verso¨hnung im Gottesdienst der Kirche. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 37.Jahr, Heft 4, 1987, pp. 246-251. (Box 33)
      - Catechisms. Printed in Dictionary of the Ecumenical Movement, pp. 131-1, 2002 (Box 33)
      - Charles Wesley: A literary overview. Printed in Charles Wesley: Poet and Theologian, Chapter 1, pp. 21-29, 1992 (Box 33)
      - Charles Wesley and Roman Catholicism. Printed in Charles Wesley: Poet and Theologian, Chapter 12, pp. 205-221., 1992 (Box 33)
      - Christlicher Gottesdienst: Lebenszusammenhang (auch) von Frauen. Printed in Edith Stein Jahrbuch, Band 5, das Christentum Zweiter Teil, 1999, pp. 63-73. (Box 33)
      - The Church in the World. Theology Today, v.53, no.2, July 1996, pp. 213-219. (Box 33)
      - The Classical Liturgical Movement in Germany and Austria: Moved by Women? Worship, v. 66, no.3, May 1992, pp. 231-251. (Box 33)
      - Doxology – Jubilate – Liturgical Theology. Archiv für Liturgiewissenschaft, Jahrgang 28, Heft 2, 1986, pp. 247-255. (Box 33)
      - Ecumenism and the Liturgy. Printed in The New Dictionary of Sacramental Worship, 1990, pp. 385-390. (Box 33)
      - Eine liturgiewissenschaftliche Wertung des Lima-Dokuments: Internationaler Kongreb der Societas Liturgica in Boston. Ökumenische Rundschau, Heft 1, Januar 1986, 35.Jahrgang, pp. 100-103. (Box 33)
      - Einheit der Kirchen – Doxologisch Konzipiert? Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 36.Jahr, Heft 4, 1986, pp. 249-261. (Box 33)
      - Elisabet und Zacharias. Printed in Dienst am Wort, v.62, Von Rut und Boas bis Judas, pp. 88-94., 1993 (Box 33)
      - Erneuerung und Pflege der Liturgie – Einheit aller, die an Christus glauben. Printed in Gottesdienst, Kirche, Gesellschaft: Interdisziplina¨re und o¨kumenische Standortbestimmungen nach 25 Jahren Liturgiereform, pp. 339-356., 1991 (Box 33)
      - A Female Christ Child in the Manger and a Woman on the Cross, Or: The Historicity of Jesus Event and the Inculturation of the Gospel. Feminist Theology, no.11, January 1996, pp. 32-45. (Box 33)
      - Feminist Liturgy. The Encyclopedia of Christianity, v.3, J-O, pp. 329-330. (Box 33)
      - Fragments of a Vision in a September 11 World. Printed in Strike Terror No More, Part 2: Visions, Chapter 12, pp. 110-115., 2002 (Box 33)
      - Frauen als Fremd-Körper im Leib Christi? Ein Blick auf den gottesdienstlichen Lebenszusammenhang der Frauen. pp. 260-265. (Box 33)
      - Frauen – Fragen – Kirche. Printed in Christsein 2001, pp. 285-286. (Box 33)
      - Frauen-freundlich. 15 Gottesdienst, 26.Jahr, 6.August 1992, pp. 116-117. (Box 33)
      - Frauengesang in der Kirche. In Lexikon für Theologie und Kirche 4 (1995), pp. 78-79. (Box 33)
      - „Geheimnisvoller Liebesverkehr zwischen Christus und Kirche". Meditation, 6.Jg., Heft 2/2000, pp. 23-27. (Box 33)
      - „ Gott, unsere Mutter, du lehrst uns, allein zu gehen… ?. Entschluss, Heft 9-10/1997, 52.Jahrgang, pp. 7-12. (Box 33)
      - Gottesdienst: Ort der Spaltung – Ort der Einheit. Una Sancta, 1/87, pp. 74-88., 1987 (Box 33)
      - Gottesdienst und Gottsuche. Neue Folge der Revue Internationale de Theologie der Ganzen Folge Hundertachtes Jahr, Heft 431, pp. 231-243. (Box 33)
      - Die gottesdienstlichen Lebenswirklichkeiten der Frauen: ein neues Forschungsgebiet. Theologische Quartalschrift, 177.Jahrgang, 4. Heft, 1997, pp. 256-270. (Box 33)
      - Gotteserfahrung in der Liturgie: Frauen-Erfahrungen. Wort und Antwort, no.34, (1993), pp. 107-109. (Box 33)
      - Das Gotteslob der Frauen? Printed in Liturgie und Frauenfrage, pp. 385-413. (Box 33)
      - Gotteslob (I). LThK, no.4, (1995), p. 930. (Box 33)
      - Gottes Wort und Gottesdienst. Zum Verhältnis von Bibel und Liturgie. Printed in Bis an die Enden der Erde, Ökumene kondet, Band 1, pp. 77-86. (Box 33)
      - Die Gnade tanzt – Katechese in Bewegung. Lebendige Katechese, 5/1 (1983), pp. 52-55. (Box 33)
      - Der Hirtenbrief der US-amerikauischen Bischofskonferenz zu Frauenfragen. Diakonia, no.22, (1991) (Box 33)
      - Die Inkulturation der Liturgie. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 39.Jahr, Heft 4, 1989, pp. 253-264. (Box 33)
      - The International Congresses of Societas Liturgica: a bibliographical survey. Studia Liturgica, no.19, (1989), pp. 111-114. (Box 33)
      - Internationale Kongresse der Societas Liturgica. Archiv für Liturgiewissenschaft, Jahrgang 30, Heft 1/2, 1988, pp. 38-40. (Box 33)
      - Jesus Christus. Printed in Bekenntnis und Zeitgeist, …und an Jesus Christus, seinen eingeborenen Sohn, unseren Herrn, pp. 68-81. (Box 33)
      - Katechumenat im Mutterleib? Printed in Glauben Lernen – Glauben feiern, pp. 61-67. (Box 33)
      - Katholisch. Printed in Wörterbuch der Feministischen Theologie, Abendmahl/Eucharistie, 2002, pp. 7-8. (Box 33)
      - Kult. Printed in Frauen Lexikon, Traditionen Fakten Perspektiven, 1988, pp. 598-601. (Box 33)
      - Lex Orandi – Lex Credendi – Lex Agendi. Archiv für Liturgiewissenschaft, Jahrgang 27, Heft 3, 1985, pp. 425-432. (Box 33)
      - 1991 (Box 33)
      - Lima Liturgy. Printed in Dictionary of the Ecumenical Movement, p. 616. (Box 33)
      - Liturgical Language: Inclusivity and Exclusivity. Studia Liturgica, no.18, (1988), pp. 132-141. (Box 33)
      - Liturgics. The Encyclopedia of Christianity, v.3, (2003), pp. 322-324. (Box 33)
      - Liturgie. Evangelisches Kirchenlexikon, pp. 149-160. (Box 33)
      - Liturgiegeschichte und Genderforschung Herausforderungen für die liturgische Tradition. Heiliger Dienst, 62. Jahrgang, 4/2008, pp. 209-223. (Box 33)
      - Liturgie und Frauenleben. Der Apfel, Nr.87, (3/2008), pp. 29-30. (Box 33)
      - Liturgie und Frausenseele ?. Kirchliche Zeitgescichte, 8.Jahrgang, Heft 2, 1995, pp. 532-544. (Box 33)
      - Liturgie und Spiritualität. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 33.Jahr, Heft 4, 1983, pp. 251-256. (Box 33)
      - Liturgie vor der Frauenfrage – Auf dem Weg zu Einer Neuen Okumene. Burgbrief, 3/92, pp. 4-17., 1992 (Box 33)
      - Liturgiewissenschaft Interkulturell. Zeitschrift für Katholische Theologie, 117.Band/1995/Heft 3, pp. 332-344. (Box 33)
      - Liturgische Bewegung – Frauen-Bewegt. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 43.Jahr, Heft 1/2, 1993, pp. 134-140. (Box 33)
      - Liturgische Communio, Kirchenspaltungen und Ökumenisches Ringen um Einheit. Heiliger Dienst, 44.Jahrgang, 4, 1990, pp. 38-46. (Box 33)
      - Liturgy – a forgotten Subject-matter of Theology?' Studia Liturgica, no.17, (1987), pp. 10-19. (Box 33)
      - Liturgy and Theology – an ongoing dialogue. Studia Liturgica, no.19, (1989), pp. 14-16. (Box 33)
      - Lyra Apostolica: Programmatic Poetry of Early Tractarianism – Prayer-Book of the Victorian Age. Internationale Cardinal-Newman-Studien, XII. Folge, pp. 103-116. (Box 33)
      - Modelle der Kirche Modelle der Liturgiewissenschaft. Ecclesia Orans, Anno X, 1993/3, pp. 339-353. (Box 33)
      - Die Nachkonziliare Liturgiereform in den USA. Printed in Liturgiereformen, Historische Studien zu einem bleibenden Grundzug des christlichen Gottesdienstes, pp. 951-964 (Box 33)
      - A Note on Notions of Catholicity in Ecumenical Reflection. Studia Liturgica, v.26, 1996, no.2, pp. 315-322. (Box 33)
      - Notes and Comments. Studia Liturgica, no.15, (1982/83), pp. 207-209., 1982-1983 (Box 33)
      - „Nuestro pan de cada dia". Una Sancta, Zeitschrift für Ökumenische Begegnung, 2/90, pp. 125-131., 1990 (Box 33)
      - Of Claire and Clairol. JFSR, 18, (2002), pp. 53-69. (Box 33)
      - Ökumene existentiell. Lebendige Seelsorge, 34, (1983), pp. 260-262. (Box 33)
      - Prayers and Practices of Women: Lex Orandi Reconfigured. Yearbook of the European Society of Women in Theological Research, v.9, 2001, pp. 63-77. (Box 33)
      - Prolegomena für eine Ökumenische Liturgiewissenschaft. Archiv für Liturgie-Wissenschaft, Jahrgang 29, Heft 1, 1987, pp. 1-18. (Box 33)
      - "Sacrosanctum Concilium" and "Worship and the Oneness of Christ's Church," Twenty-Five Years Later. Worship, v.62, no.4, July 1988, pp. 299-316. (Box 33)
      - Sacrosanctum Concilium in the 1980s: the Literature between two Anniversaries (1983-1988). Studia Liturgica, no.19, (1989), pp. 218-222. (Box 33)
      - „Sacrosanctum Concillium? und der Gottesdienst und die Einheit der Kirche Christi" 25 Jahre danach: Versuch eines Dialogs. Una Sancta, Zeitschrift fur Okumenische Begegnung, 1/88, 43.Jahrgang, pp. 75-88., 1988 (Box 33)
      - "Separated Brethren" and "Separated Sisters". Printed in Ecumenical Theology in Worship, Doctrine, and Life, Chapter 19, pp. 221-230. (Box 33)
      - Die Sprache der Liturgie. Printed in Handbuch der Liturgik, Liturgiewissenschaft in Theologie und Praxis der Kirche, pp. 798-806. (Box 33)
      - Die Struktur der dogmatischen Ausssage – weiterhin ein okumisches Problem. Una Sancta, Zeitschrift fur Okumenische Begegnung, 2/86, pp. 122-129., 1986 (Box 33)
      - Tanz. Printed in Praktisches Lexikon der Spiritualita¨t, herausgegeben von Christian Schu¨tz, 1988, pp. 1249-1251. (Box 33)
      - Tanz als Ausdruck des Glaubens. Geist und Leben, Heft 5/1982, pp. 339-352. (Box 33)
      - Tanz – Gefährte des Glaubens. Katechetische Blätter, 4/87, pp. 265-269, 1987 (Box 33)
      - „ Taufe, Eucharistie, Amt: Eine Liturgiewissenschaftliche Wertung des Lima-Dokuments ?. Liturgisches Jahrbuch, 35.Jahr, Heft 4, 1985, pp. 237-246. (Box 33)
      - „Theologie, die man singen kann …?.. Una Sancta, Zeitschrift für Ökumenische Begegnung, 2/92, pp. 123-129., 1992 (Box 33)
      - Übersetzen. Eine theologisch-biographische Zwischenbilanz. Theologische Frauenforschung in Europa, Band 1, 2000, pp. 93-100. (Box 33)
      - Unity in and through Doxology? Reflections on Worship Studies in the World Council of Churches. Studia Liturgica, v.16, no.3/4, (1986/87), pp. 1-12., 1986-1987 (Box 33)
      - Vom Christus Mädchen in der Krippe und der Frau am Kreuz. Stimmen der Zeit, Heft 4, April 1995, Band 213, pp. 251-260. (Box 33)
      - Vom Trauergewand zum Tanzkleid. Printed in "Unabla¨ssig leidet mein Herz": Christliche Verku¨ndigung angesichts von Trauer und Angst, herausgegeben von Klemens Richter, Chapter 12, pp. 60-65. (Box 33)
      - Von Fruchtwasser und Taufwasser: Eintauchen in das eine Leben? Printed in Ins Leben eintauchen! Feministisch-theologische Beitra¨ge zur Taufe, Evangelische Frauenarbeit in Wu¨rttemberg (Hrsg.), pp. 71-84. (Box 33)
      - „ die Weyber nach den mennern " ? Berliner Theologische Zeitschrift, 17.Jahrgang, Heft 2, 2000, pp. 177-193. (Box 33)
      - "Wie eine Mutter ihre Kinder zärtlich um sich schart…". Printed in Gratias Agamus, Studien zum Eucharistischen Hochgebet, pp. 45-52. (Box 33)
      - "Wie eine Mutter ihre Kinder zärtlich um sich schart…". Theologia Viatorum Neue Folge Halbjahresschrift für Theologie in der Kirche 10.Jahrgang, Heft 1, 1993, pp. 1-14. (Box 33)
      - "Wisdom Has Built Her House" (Proverbs 9:1): Gendering Sacred Space. Studia Liturgica, no.38, (2008), pp. 171-183. (Box 33)
      - "Women as Alien Bodies in the Body of Christ? The Place of Women in Worship." In Liturgy and the Body, pp. 112–20. (1995) (Box 33)
      - Women and Worship: A Bibliography. Studia Liturgica, no.19, (1989), pp. 96-110. (Box 33)
      - Women and Worship: A Bibliography Continued. Studia Liturgica, no.25, (1995), pp. 103-117. (Box 33)
      - The Women's Movement as a Liturgical Movement: A Form of Inculturation? ??? pp. 55-64. (Box 33)
      - Worship in the Ecumenical Movement. Printed in the Ecumenical Movement, pp. 1107-1112. (Box 33)
      - "Das Wort des Lebens. Zur missionarischen Dimension gottesdienstlicher Sprache." In Diemissionarische Dimension der Liturgie. Gott feiern in nachchristlicher Gesellschaft. pp. 60–69. (1998) (Box 33)
    - Reviews
      - A-F
        Including: Aus dem Leben einer Ju¨dischen Familie: das Leben Edith Steins, Kindheit und Jugend. Theologische Revue, Nr.1, Jahrgang 87, 1991, pp. 39-40 Aus Meinem Leben. Theologische Revue, Nr.1, Jahrgang 87, 1991, pp. 39-40. Charles Wesley und sein Liedgut: eine Literaturübersicht. Theologische Revue, 84.Jahrgang, Nr.6, 1988, pp. 442-450. The edge of god: new liturgical texts and contexts in conversation. Worship, November 2009, v. 83, no.6, pp. 557-558. "Ex umbris et imaginibur ": 150 Jahre Literatur zur Oxford-Bewegung. Theologische Revue, 80.Jahrgang, Nr 5, 1984, pp. 355-363. Fur ,, fromme Zionstochter" und ,, gebildete Frauenzimmer". KZG, 9.Jahrgang, Heft 1/1996.
      - G-L
        Including: Ganzheitliches Leben. Theologische Revue, Nr.1, Jahrgang 87, 1991, p. 40. Gemeinsame Liturgie in getrennten Kirchen? Theologische Revue, 88.Jahrgang, Nr.3, 1992, p. 220. God beyond Gender: Feminist Christian God-Language. The Ecumenical Review, 48, (1996), pp. 419-420. Gottesdienst – Weg zur Einheit. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 87, Nr.1, 1991, pp. 62-63. "Ich sah aus meinem Volk die Kirche wachsen!" Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 87, Nr. 3, 1991, pp. 216-217. Im Angesicht des Todes. Ein interdisziplinares Kompendium. Studia Liturgica, no.18, (1988), pp. 207-210. John Henry Newman 1801-1890. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 86, Nr. 6, 1990, pp. 479-480. John Henry Newman: The Liturgy and the Breviary. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 89, Nr. 3, 1993, pp. 187-188. Keine Frau ist ja nur Frau. Theologische Revue, Nr.1, Jahrgang 87, 1991, p. 40. Leben als Ringen um die Wahrheit. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 81, Nr. 4, 1985, pp. 293-294. Liturgiewissenschaft. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 94, Nr. 1, 1998, pp. 94-96. Liturgiewissenschaft und Frauenforschung: getrennte Schwestern? Theologische Revue, 85.Jahrgang, Nr.5, 1989, pp. 353-362.
      - M-W
        Including: Maria - für alle Frauen older über allen Frauen? Theologische Revue, 85.Jahrgang, Nr.5, 1989, pp. 405-407. Mit Gottes Volk auf Erden. 23 Gottesdienst, 23.Jahr, 30.November 1989, pp. 197. Rolle und Bedeutung des Heiligen Geistes in der Theologie John Wesleys. Theologische Revue, 85.Jahrgang, Nr.5, 1989, p. 395. The School of the Church: Worship and Christian Formation. Pro Ecclesia, Vol. VI, No.3, pp. 376-378. The Spirit of the Oxford Movement. Theologische Revue, Jahrgang 89, Nr. 3, 1993, pp. 188-189. Unsere Liebe Frau und die Frauen. Theologische Revue, 85.Jahrgang, Nr.5, 1989, pp. 404-405. Verborgenes Leben. Theologische Revue, Nr.1, Jahrgang 87, 1991, p. 40. Women and Redemption: A Theological History. Interpretation, v. 53, no. 2, April 1999, pp. 193-195.
  - Bollier, John A.
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 30.
  - Brown, Charles Reynolds
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 37.
  - Burrows, Millar
    See Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 71.
  - Calhoun, Robert L.
    See also Yale Divinity Library Record Group No. 43.
    - The Christian Meaning of Work and its Relevance Today. (North American Lay Conference on the Christian and His Daily Work, 1952) pp. 3-14. (Box 3)
    - Democracy and Natural Law. (National Law Forum, 1960) pp. 31-69. (Box 3)
    - God and the Common Life. (Letter to Dean Brown) Oct. 10, 1935. (Box 3)
    - History of Philosophy lectures transcribed by H. Ellis Finger, Jr. - Fall Term, 1940. (Box 3)
    - History of Philosophy lectures transcribed by Carl Nelson, reproduced in 1958, reprinted 1961 (297 pp.) (Box 23)
    - Irenaeus (mss. draft #1 of lecture) (Box 3)
    - Lectures on the History of Christian Doctrine, v. I-III, 1948, 537 pp. (Box 23)
    - Lectures on the History of Christian Doctrine, v. I-III, 1948, 537 pp.; reprint, 1949. (Box 3)
    - Manuscript and typescript drafts of the Lectures on the History of Doctrine, illustrative of editing process. See also George Lindbeck Papers, Record Group No. 172 for drafts and revisions leading to publication of Scripture, creed, theology: lectures on the history of Christian doctrine in the first centuries / Robert L. Calhoun; edited and with an introduction by George A. Lindbeck. (2011), 1970s? (Box 24)
    - Lectures on Systematic Theology - compiled and mimeographed by Robert H. Smith (134 pp.), 1954 (Box 23)
    - The Place of Religion in Higher Education. Hazen Pamphlets, 1949, pp. 3-10. (Box 3)
    - The Relevance of Christian Faith Today. (Addresses at Yale University Christian Mission, Feb. 3-6,1952) pp. 1-7. (Box 3)
    - Religion: Prose or Poetry? The Intercollegian, Nov 1927. (Box 3)
    - The Theological Basis for Pacifism. (Discussion with H. Richard Niebuhr at YDS, Nov 30, 1950.) (Box 3)
    - Bibliography of works of Calhoun (Box 3)
  - Carr, Aute L.
    - A View of Relationships Past and Present Binding the Yale Divinity School to the United Church of Christ. UCC Council for Higher Education Journal, Feb 1963, 2 pp. (Box 4)
  - Childs, Brevard S.
    - An Ancient and modern problem. pp. 1-9 (Box 4)
    - Biblical Theology in Crisis-Part 1 (Westminster Press, Philadelphia, pp. 13-87.), n.d. (Box 4)
    - The Birth of Moses, Journal of Biblical Literature, LXXXIV/II (1965) pp. 109-122. (Box 4)
    - Canon and Criticism. 1972 James Sprunt Lectures draft. Union Theological Seminary (Box 4)
    - The Canonical Shape of the Book of Jonah. n.d., pp. 122-128. (Box 4)
    - The Canonical Shape of the Prophetic Literature. Interpretation, v.32 (1978) pp. 46-55. (Box 4)
    - Childs v. Barr. Interpretation, Jan 1984, pp. 66-70. (Box 4)
    - Deuteronomic Formulae of the Exodus Traditions. Hebräische Wortforschung, (1967) pp. 30-39. (Box 4)